Now I want to show you how to portray the intended dynamic that you have for the piece, using the preparation beat.
So using the preparation beat if a piece starts loud, we're going to give it a big upbeat.
If it starts softer, piano, we're going to give it a smaller upbeat.
Sometimes we want to bring our plane higher too, if it's soft.
So lets do a forte, a loud entrance.
One, two, three, four.
It's a big grand upbeat.
Let's try that again.
One, two, three, four.
Now let's do a piano entrance, a soft entrance.
It's a small upbeat.
One, two, three, four.
Let's try that, sometimes it helps to raise your plane up.
If you noticed, my movements are smaller too.
One, two, three, four.